[{"id": "59049db2cf93664eb10486b0", "question": "Who met in groups of 13, also called covens?", "answer": "Witches", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a907", "question": "What major river runs through Rome?", "answer": "Tiber", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338dfb", "question": "What is the Roman name of the Greek god Hephaestus?", "answer": "Vulcan", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388e7", "question": "What is the longest one syllable word in the English language?", "answer": "Screeched", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c001", "question": "What is divided into 114 suras?", "answer": "The Quran", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a326", "question": "Who directed the 1982 film \"48 Hrs.\"?", "answer": "Walter Hill", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ffa3f9dc73aa70ea0b70b01", "question": "What does the Japanese term \"Sandai Wagyu\" translate as?", "answer": "Three Big Beefs (Sandai Wagyu are \"the three big beefs\" - Matsusaka, \u014cmi and the most-famous of all, Kobe.)", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b6c1", "question": "Who was the first figure skater to appear on a Wheaties box?", "answer": "Kristi Yamaguchi", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b05b", "question": "What was the name of the place where Washington\u2019s troops encamped in the winter of 1777?", "answer": "Valley Forge", "category": "history"}, {"id": "596dfdde9616e6c6d4eba4f9", "question": "What is the plural of the word \"crisis\"?", "answer": "Crises", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a025", "question": "What is the name of the female field reporter for Channel 5 News in the TV show \"Family Guy\"?", "answer": "Tricia Takanawa", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a90f", "question": "What major river runs through Amsterdam?", "answer": "Amstel", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339758", "question": "How many kids does Uncle Buck take care of in the movie of the same name?", "answer": "Three", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5a4d9a6708b8581f80b092bc", "question": "What did the United Nations General Assembly designate 2017 as?", "answer": "International Year of Sustainable Tourism for Development", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113395e8", "question": "In The Simpsons episode, \"Principal Charming,\" who does Skinner fall in love with?", "answer": "Patty", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133abc4", "question": "Which Italian city was severely damaged by an earthquake in 1908?", "answer": "Messina", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5ae85ff94007905755f79e8d", "question": "What is the nickname of The Ganges-Brahmaputra Delta, the largest delta in the world?", "answer": "The Green Delta", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5ffa5724c73aa70ea0b70b31", "question": "The May Day Run, held annually in England, involves thousands of what?", "answer": "Motorbikes taking the 55-mile trek from Locksbottom to Hastings.", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c83", "question": "In 2001, who gave the first concert in Oslo's Vallhall football arena?", "answer": "A-ha", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bce2", "question": "What fashion brand was co-founded by artist Beyonce?", "answer": "House of Dereon", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ab99b3e21a8909e5c332d29", "question": "Who played the main female character in the 1939 film \"Destry Rides Again\"?", "answer": "Marlene Dietrich", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "60121a4763c99d48cd169b02", "question": "According to myth, who rode the flying horse named Sleipnir?", "answer": "Sleipnir, known as the fastest horses, carried Odin the All-Father through the sky, over the seas, and across the lands.", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f0311338874", "question": "What Emily Bronte novel features Heathcliff?", "answer": "Wuthering Heights", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "59ae92ec574a5ce6b56b8233", "question": "What sport is played by the Chicago Bulls?", "answer": "Basketball", "category": "general"}, {"id": "601600fffe83fe1f2a824c5a", "question": "Why did famous Civil War photographer Mathew Brady go broke?", "answer": "No one wanted to remember the war", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fdd5eca0499cffc60b84235", "question": "What did a shepherd boy discover at Qumran, Jordan, in 1946 and 1947?", "answer": "Dead Sea Scrolls", "category": "history"}, {"id": "592eadf8f83302ff91e46482", "question": "Who had hits with the songs \"Sledgehammer\"  and \"Big Time\" in the 1980s?", "answer": "Peter Gabriel", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c5bb", "question": "What is the common term for epinephrine?", "answer": "Adrenalin", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bb73", "question": "The card game \"Penguin\" is a variation of what other card game?", "answer": "Solitaire", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339da5", "question": "Who played the role of the US president in the movie \"Being There\"?", "answer": "Jack Warden", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "591c36ad815febcc896f9269", "question": "Who runs the \"Leftorium\"?", "answer": "Ned Flanders", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fefa3c86ce05a3942286ea9", "question": "Which famous writer was San Francisco's first Black female streetcar conductor?", "answer": "Maya Angelou", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c65c", "question": "What keeps the Earth's atmosphere from leaving the planet?", "answer": "Gravity", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5901db00709c1c34536e6eb0", "question": "Ben Bailey is best known as the host of what game show?", "answer": "Cash Cab", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a08c", "question": "What band released the hit song \"Radio Gaga\"?", "answer": "Queen", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bcf3", "question": "What US state's National Guard still calls itself \"the Green Mountain Boys\"?", "answer": "Vermont", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113389d7", "question": "What artist's largest work is called \"The Night Watch\"?", "answer": "Rembrandt's", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fd82300d0de9af39e9d46ad", "question": "What was the first U.S. city to establish a police force?", "answer": "Boston", "category": "history"}, {"id": "60173c1044491cbd7c5a17a2", "question": "How did Monday get its name?", "answer": "Moon's day -- It was formerly spelled moned\u00e6i, which comes from the Old English words m\u014dnand\u00e6g and m\u014dnd\u00e6g (\u201cmoon's day\u201d).", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59dece53ea2747c8aff16d16", "question": "What is Joey's favourite food in the TV show \"Friends\"?", "answer": "Sandwiches", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ff4", "question": "What 1968 film takes place partially in the Sea of Holes?", "answer": "Yellow Submarine", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a3bc", "question": "Which capital city was once known as Byzantium?", "answer": "Istanbul", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5febae607e83c707845b20f5", "question": "What was Uranus originally called?", "answer": "Georgium Sidus", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5b571b4e67df192a942e3367", "question": "FINA is the governing body of what sport?", "answer": "Swimming", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fed261bec223966ae8f8908", "question": "In which city was the very first St. Patrick's Day celebration observed?", "answer": "According to a 2017 research by Dr. Michael Francis, the first recorded celebration of St. Patrick's Day in the world was in the city of St. Augustine in the American State of Florida.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "6008d9c9f4f3bc4a292f8612", "question": "What was the British royal family known as before becoming the House of Windsor?", "answer": "Up until 1917, the Royals were known as the Saxe-Coburgs (and sometimes as the Saxe-Coburg-Gothas).", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bab3", "question": "How many secret herbs and spices are in the original recipe chicken at KFC?", "answer": "11", "category": "general"}, {"id": "601b4ae449076251badbeabd", "question": "Who earned the nickname \"Moses\" in the Underground Railroad?", "answer": "Harriet Tubman -- One of the most well-known coordinators of the Underground Railroad, she helped more than 70 slaves to freedom.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ffb", "question": "In what movie is $200,000 of Confederate gold buried in the grave marked \"Unknown\" next to Arch Stanton?", "answer": "The Good, the Bad, and the Ugly", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ff256c931a458464a93c461", "question": "What patented structure does Apple feature in its stores?", "answer": "Glass staircase", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113397bd", "question": "What Broadway soundtrack was the best selling album of the 1960's?", "answer": "West Side Story", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5af25d36b63e5727cf5a4863", "question": "What is the name of 1992 hit single by the band \"Shakespears Sister\"?", "answer": "Stay", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b6b4", "question": "What fruit is normally squeezed into a margarita?", "answer": "Lime", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fefc0706ce05a3942286f08", "question": "Who starred as Rudy Baylor in the 1997 film \"Rainmaker\"?", "answer": "Matt Damon", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a151", "question": "Who was the first female to be inducted into the Rock and Roll Hall Of Fame?", "answer": "Aretha Franklin", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5af256d4b63e5727cf5a4840", "question": "What movie franchise action figures did Kenner start producing in the 1970s that led to its success and the popularization of the 3.75 inch action figure?", "answer": "Star Wars", "category": "general"}, {"id": "594a64972ebb971c1417fba6", "question": "Nuuk is the capital of which country?", "answer": "Greenland", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a99b", "question": "In what country would you find the active volcano \"Popocatepetl\"?", "answer": "Mexico", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c850", "question": "In what organ of the human body would you find the alveoli?", "answer": "The lungs", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5990f4d9fa5fdd6dd25324e7", "question": "Central African Republic shares its western border with which country?", "answer": "Cameroon", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f0311338932", "question": "What is the given name of the famous German composer and pianist Beethoven?", "answer": "Ludwig", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd89", "question": "What type of animal is the Japanese monster, Megalon?", "answer": "Beetle", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af6a", "question": "Who was killed by John Wilkes Booth?", "answer": "Abraham Lincoln", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c500", "question": "Angora wool is produced from what animal's coat?", "answer": "The Angora rabbit", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339363", "question": "Where did Helen and Joel get married on the TV show \"Wings\"?", "answer": "The bathroom", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59bb2853c9bff04efae6d74f", "question": "The song \"Son of My Father\" is credited as being the first number 1 UK hit to feature which instument?", "answer": "A synthesizer", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339198", "question": "What instrument does Meg White play in the band White Stripes?", "answer": "Drums", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a87a", "question": "In what city would you find the most famous street named \"La Rambla\"?", "answer": "Barcelona", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5ff51d01ff04d658268c9321", "question": "In addition to his wife, who was seated with him when Abraham Lincoln was assassinated?", "answer": "Clara Harris and Henry Rathbone.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133921c", "question": "What city did the band U2 form in?", "answer": "Dublin", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b4c", "question": "What mode of transportation did Gary Numan sing about in a 1980 Top 10 hit?", "answer": "Cars", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a2e4", "question": "When was actor W. C. Fields born?", "answer": "1880", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339066", "question": "What does the Latin word \"Verbatim\" literally means?", "answer": "Word for word", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b10a", "question": "Which US President fathered children with former slave Sally Hemmings?", "answer": "Thomas Jefferson", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b2ea", "question": "What US state has been led by Theodore and Franklin Roosevelt?", "answer": "New York", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a347", "question": "What decade did the TV special \"It's the Great Pumpkin, Charlie Brown\" come out in?", "answer": "1960s", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5963726b967692ea851899bf", "question": "Approximately 95% of the jellyfish's body is made up of what?", "answer": "Water", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b259", "question": "Which amendment to the US Constitution deals with the right to bear arms?", "answer": "Second", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133921f", "question": "What is the collective name for Italian-made western movies?", "answer": "Spaghetti westerns", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a30", "question": "Which Biblical figure by Michelangelo has been called \"the most recognizable statue in the history of sculpture\"?", "answer": "David", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b802", "question": "What is the point value of the letter Q in the standard game of Scrabble?", "answer": "10", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113394cb", "question": "Einstein was the name of what character's dog in the film \"Back to the Future\"?", "answer": "Emmett Brown", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fec85c7ec223966ae8f8809", "question": "In the movie \"The Shawshank Redemption\", warden Norton often whistled what hymn song?", "answer": "\"A Mighty Fortress is Our God\"", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a577", "question": "Washington D.C. is located in which state?", "answer": "None, it is not part of any US state", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133934e", "question": "Who played Alex's sister, Mallory, on the TV show \"Family Ties\"?", "answer": "Justine Bateman", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bed9", "question": "In golf what would you put in your shag bag?", "answer": "Practice balls", "category": "general"}, {"id": "6014c99afbde8045e48466f0", "question": "How many plates make up the Earth's crust?", "answer": "15 -- The Earth's crust is made up with 7 major and 8 minor plates.", "category": "science"}, {"id": "59f9b8dc364247bf200fb884", "question": "Whose debut solo album was titled \"I Got Dem Ol' Kozmic Blues Again Mama!\"?", "answer": "Janis Joplin's", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "600f6ed4a9e54d890926f6cb", "question": "Which American city was home to the world's first skyscraper?", "answer": "Chicago -- The Home Insurance Building was 180 ft. tall.  Constructed in 1885, it was demolished in 1931.", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "59ae9384574a5ce6b56b823d", "question": "Who was the only man to knock out Muhammad Ali in a heavyweight title fight?", "answer": "Larry Holmes", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a447", "question": "Which river runs through Paris?", "answer": "Seine", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b407", "question": "Who was the first dog in space?", "answer": "Laika", "category": "history"}, {"id": "6010c1540775fa611bce67c2", "question": "Dysmorphia is a mental disorder characterized by what?", "answer": "The obsessive idea that some aspect of one's own body part or appearance is severely flawed.", "category": "science"}, {"id": "59ae956c574a5ce6b56b8255", "question": "What animals does a hippophobe fear?", "answer": "Horses", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339265", "question": "What was Paul McCartney's Bond theme?", "answer": "Live and Let Die", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bde8", "question": "Who invented the method he called \"rope-a-dope\"?", "answer": "Muhammad Ali", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b141", "question": "Who did Bill Clinton defeat in the 1996 US Presidential election?", "answer": "Bob Dole", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113395df", "question": "In The Simpsons episode, \"Treehouse of Horror II,\" Mr. Burns pretends to be Davy Crockett while wearing what on his head?", "answer": "Homer's brain", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fdff56e1cf6db9ac4808cea", "question": "Where is the mythological birthplace of the Incas?", "answer": "Isla del Sol, Bolivia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "592eafdcf83302ff91e46496", "question": "Who directed the 1999 film \"American Beauty\"?", "answer": "Sam Mendes", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338db5", "question": "What title character of a classic 1891 novel is arrested at Stonehenge?", "answer": "Tess of the D'Urbervilles", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d0b", "question": "What movie's first sequel featured the subtitle \"State of the Union\"?", "answer": "xXx", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ff66b1e52a821ff76ae8b0c", "question": "People who scavenged the sewers of London during the Victoria era were called what?", "answer": "Tosher", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe733a8eec85e375820b223", "question": "In a Nazi concentration camp, a black triangle identified a prisoner as what?", "answer": "Asocial", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f46", "question": "Who created the character of Br'er Bear?", "answer": "Joel Chandler Harris", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe4b60606d333868d34d6ee", "question": "As which Russian leader was Vladimir Ulyanov better known?", "answer": "Lenin", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ff7c3462b316f4693fb67a7", "question": "Monterey Jack is a type of what?", "answer": "Cheese", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113399a5", "question": "What Hanna-Barbera cartoon characters were patterned after Ed Norton from the TV series \"The Honeymooners\"?", "answer": "Yogi Bear and Barney Rubble", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a77", "question": "Eric Burdon was the front-man of what two 1960's bands?", "answer": "The Animals and War", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339375", "question": "In the movie \"Cast Away\", how long was Chuck Nolan marooned on the island?", "answer": "4 years", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bb5d", "question": "What ice cream chain once sold a ketchup-flavored ice cream?", "answer": "Baskin-Robbins", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b2b0", "question": "What nation was led by Sargon the Great?", "answer": "Akkad", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133ca72", "question": "What is measured in fathoms?", "answer": "Depth of water", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5989a89acb8751d53e7d75fb", "question": "Who won the fourth Super Bowl?", "answer": "Kansas City Chiefs", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c507", "question": "What sensory organ do starfish have at the end of each arm?", "answer": "Eye", "category": "science"}, {"id": "58d1193d4fea7fe947a2228c", "question": "Which song from the \"White Album\" was originally titled \"Maharishi\"?", "answer": "Sexy Sadie", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5921fd54a4edfd43a087adc9", "question": "How many holes can be found in the standard bowling ball?", "answer": "3", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd7e", "question": "According to the Bible, who died at the ripe old age of 930?", "answer": "Adam", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339360", "question": "What \"Smokey and the Bandit\" movie star played the blacksmith on \"Gunsmoke\"?", "answer": "Burt Reynolds", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113399ac", "question": "Blues legend McKinley Morganfield was better known by what name?", "answer": "Muddy Waters", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339217", "question": "What Stealers Wheel hit is heard in the movie \"Reservoir Dogs\"?", "answer": "Stuck in the Middle with You", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339bda", "question": "Mark Wahlberg has a tattoo of what popular musician on his left shoulder?", "answer": "Bob Marley", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe4df2906d333868d34d71f", "question": "Which human ancestor was the first to discover fire?", "answer": "Homo Erectus", "category": "history"}, {"id": "58dba63b874c93a3298b2157", "question": "In the film \"Men In Black 3\", what did Agent K like to eat in order to think better?", "answer": "Pie", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5989a8abcb8751d53e7d75fd", "question": "Who won Super Bowl IV?", "answer": "Kansas City Chiefs", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c0de", "question": "What is IRC an acronym for?", "answer": "Internet relay chat", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338bbc", "question": "Who was the twin brother of Artemis?", "answer": "Apollo", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5ff0adf0e662d71a53650fb5", "question": "Who became famous for painting New Mexico landscapes from her Model A Ford?", "answer": "Georgia O\u2019Keeffe", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b6a0", "question": "A cat-o'-nine tails is a type of what?", "answer": "Whip", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fea80c8ff048f679a45ac1c", "question": "The Black Death was caused by fleas carried by what animal?", "answer": "Rodents", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113396de", "question": "Which pop group was initially named \"The Pendletones\"?", "answer": "The Beach Boys", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a612", "question": "Which is the third largest Caribbean island?", "answer": "Jamaica", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ae62", "question": "The sale of what was prohibited in the US during The Prohibition?", "answer": "Alcohol", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a9e6", "question": "On what sea is the Crimea?", "answer": "Black Sea", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5a162baaf01ec323f849172b", "question": "What type of creature is a Silverback?", "answer": "A gorilla", "category": "science"}, {"id": "6010ca540775fa611bce67f7", "question": "What mythical beast suffers from a condition known as lycanthropy?", "answer": "Werewolves", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd0c", "question": "What was the original brand of cereal whose mascot was Sugar Bear?", "answer": "Super Sugar Crisp", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aa17", "question": "What country borders Egypt to the south?", "answer": "Sudan", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "595643fe803c1f1ebcc4a032", "question": "Ketchup was sold in the 1830\u2019s as what?", "answer": "Medicine", "category": "general"}, {"id": "601b4c2749076251badbeace", "question": "How many U.S. Presidents fathered no children?", "answer": "Five -- George Washington, James Polk, Warren Harding, James Buchanan, and Andrew Jackson fathered no children.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339064", "question": "Which Latin word is used to express the meaning \"word for word\"?", "answer": "Verbatim", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "592ead28f83302ff91e46477", "question": "Which play is generally accepted to be Shakespeare's last, fully completed play before his death?", "answer": "The Tempest", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba48", "question": "What US city hosts the world's largest hot air balloon festival?", "answer": "Albuquerque", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe8fc3001dd7bf43be5e859", "question": "What does GIF stand for?", "answer": "Graphics Interchange Format", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fea7e3dff048f679a45ac0a", "question": "Autophobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Being alone", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339143", "question": "When did Benjamin Britten's opera \"Death in Venice\" premier?", "answer": "1973", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113390df", "question": "In which play does Dame Pliant appear?", "answer": "The Alchemist", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e6c", "question": "Who played the blind character in the movie \"Daredevil\"?", "answer": "Ben Affleck", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59db751e0ab2c8f322317fe4", "question": "Peridot is the birthstone for which month?", "answer": "August", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a27f", "question": "Vinnie Jones was associated with which sport?", "answer": "Soccer", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113393b5", "question": "Who did Ed Wood meet in the movie by the same name?", "answer": "Bela Lugosi", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c4d1", "question": "Which two numbers are used in the binary system?", "answer": "Zero and one", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a518", "question": "Sofia is the capital of which nation?", "answer": "Bulgaria", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "597742ce284458f1d7854422", "question": "What two Coaches on \"The Voice\" US have been on from season 1 through season 14?", "answer": "Blake Shelton and Adam Levine", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fea78d2ff048f679a45abde", "question": "What vegetable family does Calabrese broccoli come from?", "answer": "Cabbage family", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a76d", "question": "What lake in Oregon was created about 7,000 years ago by the eruption of Mount Mazama?", "answer": "Crater Lake", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339bf6", "question": "What US state was actress Julia Roberts born in?", "answer": "Georgia", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b0ba", "question": "In what town was FDR's \"Little White House\" located?", "answer": "Warm Springs, Georgia", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a8fc", "question": "What famous street follows the line of a twelve-foot stockade begun in 1653 by Peter Stuyvesant?", "answer": "Wall Street", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "601370f61381754895396387", "question": "Who said, \"We came, we saw, we kicked its ass\"?", "answer": "Dr. Peter Venkman in the film \"Ghostbusters\"", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a47c", "question": "In which city is the European Court of Justice?", "answer": "Luxembourg", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339240", "question": "What George Michael song was banned by the BBC and re-edited three times for MTV?", "answer": "I Want Your Sex", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59cdb2e065ff7d326b622a7b", "question": "Which Apollo space mission put the first men on the moon?", "answer": "Apollo 11", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe9f5a4ff048f679a45aad7", "question": "Which of your organs can regenerate itself up to 60%?", "answer": "Liver", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c998", "question": "Caries refers to decay in what?", "answer": "Teeth", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a19a", "question": "Which two TV series from the 1980s featured a character named Uncle Jesse?", "answer": "Full House and The Dukes of Hazzard", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd91", "question": "What Japanese word for \"wave person\" refers to a masterless samurai?", "answer": "Ronin", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fefc56f6ce05a3942286f3e", "question": "What 19th century opera singer was known as the \"Swedish Nightingale\"?", "answer": "Jenny Lind", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a37c", "question": "What city would one find the Louvre in?", "answer": "Paris", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5cd40ca4685cf15b733e9890", "question": "How many furlongs are there in a mile?", "answer": "8", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ae02", "question": "Who was the first human in outer space?", "answer": "Yuri Gagarin", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a779", "question": "What body of water does the Colorado river empty into?", "answer": "The Gulf of California", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c76", "question": "What philosopher/author lived on the shores of Walden Pond?", "answer": "Henry David Thoreau", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133aeb2", "question": "When did the \"War of Jenkins' Ear\", waged between Britain and Spain, end?", "answer": "1748", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fdfbfbd003d27d341092bd8", "question": "How much lower does the Dead Sea get every year?", "answer": "One meter", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "58b371481c3f17ccc40c8e1e", "question": "Approximately how much more beer would you get in a pint served in the UK compared to one served in the US?", "answer": "95 mL", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a3b1", "question": "Which country contains Lake Assal, the lowest point on mainland Africa?", "answer": "Djibouti", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fdd5e060499cffc60b84233", "question": "What Egyptian monster feasts on the heart of someone unworthy of eternal life?", "answer": "Ammut", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe93d776bd93ce3a4e5f6b6", "question": "Shale is what kind of rock?", "answer": "Sedimentary rock", "category": "science"}, {"id": "58f565ef33a95c66dc4fe75c", "question": "Bismarck is the capital of which US state?", "answer": "North Dakota", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c56e", "question": "What is the atomic number of the chemical element gold?", "answer": "79", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388e2", "question": "What year was the first book of the \"Bourne Trilogy\" series first published?", "answer": "1980", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133acdf", "question": "Who invented the radio alarm clock?", "answer": "James F. Reynolds", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b6d8", "question": "What pro sport did Althea Gibson play when her tennis career ended?", "answer": "Golf", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b246", "question": "The US's first law school for women was named for what cross-dressing Shakespearean character?", "answer": "Portia", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c264", "question": "What constitutes 12 percent of an egg's weight?", "answer": "The shell", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113390af", "question": "What year was the novel \"The Catcher in the Rye\" first published?", "answer": "1951", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338b0e", "question": "Who is Johnny Storm better known as in the comic book series \"Fantastic Four\"?", "answer": "Human Torch", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c688", "question": "Who took a leave of absence in the mid 1940's from his position at Cal Tech to direct the Manhattan Project?", "answer": "Robert Oppenheimer", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aa7a", "question": "What is the capital of Bhutan?", "answer": "Thimphu", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b6bb", "question": "The logo of Mack Trucks is what animal?", "answer": "A bulldog", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ffa5658c73aa70ea0b70b2a", "question": "What color do people wear for the New Year in Brazil?", "answer": "White", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "6015e6bcfe83fe1f2a824bd1", "question": "Who gave Queen Elizabeth I the soubriquet \"Gloriana\"?", "answer": "Edmund Spenser, in his epic poem \"The Faerie Queene\"", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe9f4bdff048f679a45aaca", "question": "Lilapsophobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Tornadoes and hurricanes", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5aab2f1d58d116dab4aecb46", "question": "Banjul is the capital of which country?", "answer": "The Gambia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e23", "question": "In what country was Zubin Mehta born?", "answer": "India", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe6991c20565ad31a57c741", "question": "What is the name of the Miami Heat mascot?", "answer": "Burnie", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b9a1", "question": "What does the abbreviation NATO stand for?", "answer": "North Atlantic Treaty Organization", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd38", "question": "In which nation did the woven-yarn craft of \"God's eyes\" originate?", "answer": "Mexico", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e1f", "question": "For an SNL monologue, who once played the banjo with an arrow through his head?", "answer": "Steve Martin", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e3d", "question": "What children's classic first chapter is titled \"In the Drain\"?", "answer": "Stuart Little", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f0311338966", "question": "What is the English title of the Manet painting depicting a nude woman enjoying a picnic with two clothed men?", "answer": "The Luncheon on the Grass", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ada1", "question": "Harry Alonzo Longabaugh was better known as who?", "answer": "Sundance Kid", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59a1a3f312f2a7826b9b872b", "question": "What do the letters in UNESCO's name stand for?", "answer": "United Nations Educational, Scientific and Cultural Organization", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5febaee37e83c707845b20f8", "question": "What year was the first black hole discovered?", "answer": "1971", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c3f4", "question": "What vitamin is milk fortified with in the US to combat rickets?", "answer": "Vitamin D", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c656", "question": "Which organ is responsible for creating urine?", "answer": "The kidneys", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ff9", "question": "In Greek mythology, who hired Daedalus to construct the Labyrinth?", "answer": "King Minos", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "601b4ba949076251badbeac6", "question": "The first North American\u00a0English seasonal camp was founded where?", "answer": "St. John's, Newfoundland -- In 1583, Sir\u00a0Humphrey Gilbert, by the\u00a0royal prerogative\u00a0of\u00a0Queen Elizabeth I, founded\u00a0St. John's.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5a4a954861d1b4d384d5d677", "question": "What is pumpernickel?", "answer": "A type of German bread", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339102", "question": "Who wrote the opera \"Carmen\"?", "answer": "Georges Bizet", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a2fe", "question": "Who played the role of Arnold on the ABC sitcom \"Happy Days\"?", "answer": "Pat Morita", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e51", "question": "What athlete had a part in the movie \"Mitchell\"?", "answer": "Merlin Olsen", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c03a", "question": "Where is the Popliteal Fossa located?", "answer": "Back of the knee", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c03d", "question": "Sociophobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Society and social situations", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338be8", "question": "Who wrote the novel \"A Clockwork Orange\"?", "answer": "Anthony Burgess", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b90f", "question": "What party game involves a shifting shortage of seats?", "answer": "Musical chairs", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e78", "question": "During what war was the novel \"Cold Mountain\" set?", "answer": "US Civil War", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a617", "question": "What country's major seaport is Alexandria?", "answer": "Egypt", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c2af", "question": "What is the Scoville unit a measure of?", "answer": "The spicy heat of a chili pepper.", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c01", "question": "The novel \"Gone With the Wind\" was written by who?", "answer": "Margaret Mitchell", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5febac047e83c707845b20ea", "question": "What was the name of the last known Pinta Island tortoise?", "answer": "Lonesome George", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fd66bf8a5bfecdd737e088c", "question": "What was the original name of Vaseline?", "answer": "Wonder jelly", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339834", "question": "What movie won an Oscar for \"Best Picture\" in 1991?", "answer": "Dances With Wolves", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339119", "question": "Who is the protagonist of H. G. Wells' \"The Island of Doctor Moreau\"?", "answer": "Edward Prendick", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b653", "question": "On the classic Monopoly board, which property has a misspelled name?", "answer": "Marvin Gardens", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b49", "question": "Who played Al Borland on the TV show \"Home Improvement\"?", "answer": "Richard Karn", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ccf78d0b37b32637bdc44bb", "question": "What is the name of Marvin and Trina's son in the musical \"Falsettos\"?", "answer": "Jason", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fd2d0cf2596a59cbdfbd381", "question": "Who first said, \"When you reach the end of your rope, tie a knot and hang on\"?", "answer": "Abraham Lincoln", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b7cd", "question": "What route runs from Chicago to Los Angeles?", "answer": "Route 66", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c313", "question": "How many times a year does the sun rise and set at the North Pole?", "answer": "Once", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a641", "question": "Lake Champlain is located in Vermont and in which other state?", "answer": "New York", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5b6992cbe762b54eb9be9426", "question": "What country has the calling code +20?", "answer": "Egypt", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a0c1", "question": "Which 1954 film won eight Oscars?", "answer": "On the Waterfront", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113390fc", "question": "What year did Frederick Forsyth publish the novel \"The Deceiver\"?", "answer": "1991", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "6000edf09a72b906b34e3cf2", "question": "What is the name of the largest vein in the human body?", "answer": "The inferior vena cava", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388bd", "question": "What peg-legged pirate had a parrot named Captain Flint?", "answer": "Long John Silver", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5a25f14f6682715b82711cde", "question": "What year was the ice cream cone patented in the US?", "answer": "1903", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5937ea7a08d98002fdd633a3", "question": "Assam, darjeeling and oolong are all types of what?", "answer": "Tea", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe4b38f06d333868d34d6d9", "question": "Which song produced a Christmas truce during World War I?", "answer": "\"Silent Night\"", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe7cf01877e98cb97778a49", "question": "Where is the \"Cathedral of Rum\"?", "answer": "Puerto Rico", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe73e84eec85e375820b275", "question": "Which U.S. Lake has its own version of the Bermuda Triangle?", "answer": "Lake Michigan", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c325", "question": "What does the acronym RPM stand for?", "answer": "Revolutions per minute", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113395ba", "question": "In The Simpsons, what is the monstrous truck at the Monster Truck Rally called?", "answer": "Truckasaurus", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f12", "question": "Which professional wrestler starred in the 1988 movie \"They Live\"?", "answer": "\"Rowdy\" Roddy Piper", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388e5", "question": "What is known as a \"Magnum Opus\"?", "answer": "The greatest, most popular or most renowned achievement of a writer, artist or composer", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "58ec23a98dc25ca9e12ef632", "question": "What word describes \"a series of rulers from the same family\"?", "answer": "Dynasty", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe6a09020565ad31a57c796", "question": "What was the Statue of Liberty originally designed to commemorate?", "answer": "Freed enslaved people", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a5d5", "question": "What is the capital of Kosovo?", "answer": "Pristina", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133903e", "question": "Which poisonous concoction was Socrates given to drink to carry out his death sentence?", "answer": "Hemlock", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5b571bf267df192a942e336f", "question": "Who wrote the dystopian novel \"A Clockwork Orange\"?", "answer": "Anthony Burgess", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "6015e292fe83fe1f2a824ba0", "question": "How did the Western Allies respond to Germany\u2019s invasion of Russia?", "answer": "They sent supplies and intelligence to Russia.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "58ec24c58dc25ca9e12ef63a", "question": "What was the very first Andrew Lloyd Webber musical to be adapted to film?", "answer": "Jesus Christ Superstar", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fd81b26d0de9af39e9d4675", "question": "What was the capital city of the Aztec Empire?", "answer": "Tenochtitlan", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e7a", "question": "Which TV show used the song \"A Little Less Conversation\" by Elvis Presley as its theme song?", "answer": "Las Vegas", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ce5", "question": "What is Mr. Belvedere's given name?", "answer": "Lynn", "category": "entertainment"}]